that are edible? What if we could completely change the experience, like you see with that absinthe serving that is completely 3D printed? And what if we could begin to put ingredients and colors and flavors in every taste, which means not only delicious foods but the promise of personalized nutrition around the corner? And that gets me to one of the biggest deals about 3D printing. With 3D printing, complexity is free. The printer doesn't care if it makes the most rudimentary shape or the most complex shape, and that is completely turning design and manufacturing on its head as we know it. Many people think that 3D printing will be the end of manufacturing as we know it. I think that it's the opportunity to put tomorrow's technology in the hands of youngsters that will create endless abundance of job opportunities, and with that, everybody can become an expert maker and an expert manufacturer. That will take new tools. Not everybody knows how to use CAD, so we're developing haptics, perceptual devices that will allow you to touch and feel your designs as if you play with digital clay. When you do things like that, and we also developed things that take physical photographs that are instantly printable, it will make it easier to create content, but with all of the unimagined, we will also have the unintended, like democratized counterfeiting and ubiquitous illegal possession. So many people ask me, will we have a 3D printer in every home? I think it's the wrong question to ask. The right question to ask is, how will 3D printing change my life? Or, in other words, what room in my house will 3D printing fit in? So everything that you see here has been 3D printed, including these shoes at the Amsterdam fashion show. Now, these are not my grandfather's shoes. These are shoes that represent the continuation of his passion for hyper-local manufacturing. My grandfather didn't get to see Nike printing cleats for the recent Super Bowl, and my father didn't get to see me standing in my hybridized 3D printed shoes. He passed away three years ago. But Chuck Hull, the man that invented it all, is right here in the house today, and thanks to him, I can say, thanks to his invention, I can say that I am a cobbler too, and by standing in these shoes I am honoring my past while manufacturing the future. Thank you. (Applause)
que fueran comestibles? ¿Qué pasaría si pudiéramos cambiar completamente la experiencia, como ven con la funda de absenta que está totalmente impresa en 3D? Y ¿qué pasa si pudiéramos empezar a añadir ingredientes y colores y sabores de todos los gustos, que no solamente significara comida deliciosa sino la promesa de una nutrición personalizada a la vuelta de la esquina? Y eso me lleva a una de las cosas más grandes sobre la impresión 3D. Con la impresión 3D, la complejidad es gratuita. A la impresora le da igual si crea la forma más rudimentaria o la forma más compleja, y eso está volcando completamente el diseño y la fabricación como los conocemos. Muchos piensan que la impresión 3D será el fin de la fabricación como la conocemos. Yo pienso que es la oportunidad de poner la tecnología del futuro en las manos de los jóvenes que crearán abundancia sin fin de oportunidades de empleo, y con eso, todos pueden convertirse en creadores expertos y fabricantes expertos. Eso precisará nuevas herramientas. No todos saben utilizar CAD, y estamos desarrollando dispositivos hápticos de percepción que permitirán tocar y sentir los diseños como si se jugara con arcilla digital. Al hacer cosas como esas, y también desarrollar cosas que toman fotografías físicas que son imprimibles al instante, se facilita la creación del contenido, pero con todo lo inimaginado, también tendremos falsificación democratizada no intencional y posesión ilegal ubicua. Mucha gente me pregunta, si tendremos una impresora 3D en todos los hogares. Pienso que la pregunta no es correcta. La pregunta correcta que hay que hacerse es, ¿cómo la impresión 3D cambiará mi vida? En otras palabras, ¿en qué habitación de mi casa encajará la impresión 3D? Y todo lo que ven aquí fue impreso en 3D, incluyendo estos zapatos en la feria de la moda de Ámsterdam. Bien, no son los zapatos de mi abuelo. Esos zapatos representan la continuación de su pasión por la fabricación hiperlocal. Mi abuelo no llegó a conocer los tacos impresos de Nike para el último Super Bowl Y mi padre no llegó a verme usando mis zapatos hibridados impresos en 3D. Él falleció hace tres años. Pero Chuck Hull, el hombre que lo inventó todo, está aquí mismo en el salón, y gracias a él, puedo decir, gracias a su invención, puedo decir que soy también zapatero, Y al usar estos zapatos estoy honrando mi pasado mientras fabrico mi futuro. Gracias. (Aplausos)